<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<package packagerversion="1.9.1" version="2.0" xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/package-2.0" xmlns:tasks="http://pear.php.net/dtd/tasks-1.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/tasks-1.0 http://pear.php.net/dtd/tasks-1.0.xsd http://pear.php.net/dtd/package-2.0 http://pear.php.net/dtd/package-2.0.xsd">
 <name>WINCACHE</name>
 <channel>pecl.php.net</channel>
 <summary>Windows Cache Extension for PHP</summary>
 <description>Windows Cache Extension for PHP is a PHP accelerator that is used to increase the speed of PHP applications running on Windows and Windows Server. Once the Windows Cache Extension for PHP is enabled and loaded by the PHP engine, PHP applications can take advantage of the functionality without any code modifications. The extension includes PHP opcode cache, file system cache and relative path cache. In addition the extension provides cache API&apos;s and a PHP session handler.</description>
 <lead>
  <name>Ruslan Yakushev</name>
  <user>ruslany</user>
  <email>ruslany@microsoft.com</email>
  <active>no</active>
 </lead>
 <lead>
  <name>Venkat Raman Don</name>
  <user>donraman</user>
  <email>don.raman@microsoft.com</email>
  <active>no</active>
 </lead>
 <lead>
  <name>Kanwaljeet Singla</name>
  <user>ksingla</user>
  <email>ksingla@microsoft.com</email>
  <active>no</active>
 </lead>
 <lead>
  <name>Eric Stenson</name>
  <user>ericsten</user>
  <email>ericsten@php.net</email>
  <active>yes</active>
 </lead>
 <date>2015-03-23</date>
 <time>21:16:35</time>
 <version>
  <release>1.3.7.4</release>
  <api>1.3.0</api>
 </version>
 <stability>
  <release>stable</release>
  <api>stable</api>
 </stability>
 <license uri="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php">BSD License</license>
 <notes>
1.3.7.4:
- Fix uninitialized variable issue that leads to av (null zend_error_cb).
- Increase the timeout used to wait for other processes to finish initialization.
- Re-order initialization such that User Cache will still work even if file cache fails to init.
- Remove noisy ASSERTs.
- Improve error checking in shared memory heap management functions.
- Fix alloc bug in wincache_file_get_contents.
- Enable setting of debuglevel and reroute_enabled from .user.ini.
- Move shared memory segments out of the Windows System Pagefile. Added new configuration setting wincache.filemapdir to control where the temp files are created.
- Refine VM base address selection for shared memory maps.
- Ensure all named objects created with Global prefix when apppoolid is set.
 </notes>
 <contents>
  <dir name="/">
   <file md5sum="a24ac63aa402b1799f5fcbc3e5e21039" name="config.w32" role="doc" />
   <file md5sum="164b10da8aa64d4f305e529bb6d2fb34" name="INSTALL" role="doc" />
   <file md5sum="1c64bd0f2de4ff7396a2cc7ec3847c55" name="LICENSE" role="doc" />
   <file md5sum="1f02671e8cf6b4f24626425efcd29c55" name="php_wincache.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="3f0a83cc1b88d8e8e66995c2209efbd0" name="php_wincache.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="60c9614b95bc9b7168bb99cbd87f093a" name="precomp.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="2a7b36d8d1271317b7064f9c9f83a551" name="template.rc" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="72a7b3d598fbf38cd2ff8d5c834a73fc" name="wincache_alloc.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="4fdb2ce53160360ac25d626c0f11b3fd" name="wincache_alloc.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="31b38b63a280bac76ed3b5982632eee3" name="wincache_aplist.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="17a182756d68eed43d56ca70f4f81e06" name="wincache_aplist.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="8fe6332e4cfcb50be8a822c304434ce6" name="wincache_debug.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="714177fd8855efd91978a3b90daf27bb" name="wincache_debug.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="e998b305337338323a490965261f835c" name="wincache_error.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="a29f46741dabdcde9080c7a7a2f4dee5" name="wincache_error.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="e59d9383331c873c208c5a0b903fc0a0" name="wincache_fcache.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="979bafd12f5a00001fbe386ee901b4ca" name="wincache_fcache.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="d5a2eee41c542948b312804c7c7d8642" name="wincache_fcnotify.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="71e5876af1210ac3dcc2c3dcbff69d37" name="wincache_fcnotify.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="1a94775a287ad11f05d1f0ed6f6fcab2" name="wincache_filemap.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="826f2f82cc72645ff50db2f901796cf0" name="wincache_filemap.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="1073d981c1332f5827f9c817aafc6a30" name="wincache_lock.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="33ae833d6efa2e928226f9855c939eb1" name="wincache_lock.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="5617bcc15927eccc142f8623456fc8ca" name="wincache_ocache.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="62b7191e0dce8f61f6437168739f09e7" name="wincache_ocache.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="c34c9c3489b5d6009524ca38cbc6b204" name="wincache_opcopy.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="26d6fc4f35e3c71ef18ac19f9b39604f" name="wincache_opcopy.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="49fd132d72105a6d0287be51b956c008" name="wincache_rplist.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="4177037b878c35fd4994efc7228b9a66" name="wincache_rplist.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="42912d05c1b4a09f44db300a1ab50625" name="wincache_session.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="c41490fb8c36e4ed2b183d3aa4e30a96" name="wincache_session.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="9c937fa8b4881a817444bb3c51bf6f68" name="wincache_string.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="d0628ee98795f98c54ab6349c3dc376e" name="wincache_string.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="bbf88d92f55d97d8317983946b19eee9" name="wincache_utils.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="924173bb14fccd0d0962c855a4c4173c" name="wincache_utils.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="34706b702a8cfa1232dcae610c0f2f57" name="wincache_zvcache.h" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="263a0b3f1afe645df72eb9b71b23d77e" name="wincache_zvcache.c" role="src" />
   <file md5sum="835d3b81539420e86f75f28c175f12a2" name="wincache.php" role="php" />
  </dir>
 </contents>
 <dependencies>
  <required>
   <php>
    <min>5.2.0</min>
   </php>
   <pearinstaller>
    <min>1.4.0</min>
   </pearinstaller>
  </required>
 </dependencies>
 <providesextension>wincache</providesextension>
 <extsrcrelease />
 <changelog>
  <release>
   <date>2015-01-10</date>
   <version>
    <release>1.3.7.0</release>
    <api>1.3.0</api>
   </version>
   <stability>
    <release>beta</release>
    <api>beta</api>
   </stability>
   <notes>
1.3.7.0:
- Remove undocumented Wincache functions
- Rip out detours/reroute.ini stuff
- Add cache-aware wrappers to correctly reroute internal PHP functions
- Add configuration to enable/disable rerouted functions (on/off)
   </notes>
  </release>
  <release>
   <date>2014-06-18</date>
   <version>
    <release>1.3.6.1</release>
    <api>1.2.0</api>
   </version>
   <stability>
    <release>stable</release>
    <api>stable</api>
   </stability>
   <notes>
1.3.6.1:
- PHP 5.6 support.
- BUG #67466: Mapping error during startup leads to unpredictable AV in opcode cache
   </notes>
  </release>
  <release>
   <date>2014-03-28</date>
   <version>
    <release>1.3.5.3</release>
    <api>1.2.0</api>
   </version>
   <stability>
    <release>beta</release>
    <api>stable</api>
   </stability>
   <notes>
1.3.5.3 beta:
- Fixed several potential AVs while holding cross-process locks
   </notes>
  </release>
  <release>
   <date>2013-08-20</date>
   <version>
    <release>1.3.5.0</release>
    <api>1.2.0</api>
   </version>
   <stability>
    <release>stable</release>
    <api>stable</api>
   </stability>
   <notes>
1.3.5.0 release:
- Compiled for PHP 5.5
- Opcode Cache is disabled by default for PHP 5.5 because Opcache is available in Core
- Added support for traits and trait aliases
   </notes>
  </release>
  <release>
   <date>2012-05-24</date>
   <version>
    <release>1.3.1</release>
    <api>1.2.0</api>
   </version>
   <stability>
    <release>beta</release>
    <api>beta</api>
   </stability>
   <notes>
1.3.1 beta:
- Increased User Cache max to 1024 (1GB)
- Fixed issue with rmdir
   </notes>
  </release>
  <release>
   <date>2012-04-24</date>
   <version>
    <release>1.3.0</release>
    <api>1.2.0</api>
   </version>
   <stability>
    <release>beta</release>
    <api>beta</api>
   </stability>
   <notes>
1.3.0 release:
- Added support for PHP 5.4, which includes support for the following:
  * Zend Engine 2.4 structures (znode_op, zend_class_entry, etc.).
  * Interned strings.
  * Stop hooking zend_stream_open_function, due to breaking change in Zend 2.4.
  * Removed PG(safe_mode) and php_checkuid() checks for Zend 2.4.
- Cleaned up const compiler warnings.
- Cleaned up random comments to make them PECL coding standards conformant.
   </notes>
  </release>
  <release>
   <date>2010-06-30</date>
   <version>
    <release>1.2.0</release>
    <api>1.2.0</api>
   </version>
   <stability>
    <release>beta</release>
    <api>beta</api>
   </stability>
   <notes>
1.2.0 release:
- Added functionality to supply wincache with APP_POOL_ID. Patch provided by Richard Quadling.
- Fixed wordpress plugin install issue which was caused by open folder in distributed file change notification system.
- Added utils_resolve_path for PHP 5.2 and using it for getting fullpath.
- Made distributed file notification system more robust.
- Changed lock usage in aplist_fcache_get.
- Added wincache_filesize.
- Using wincache_resolve_path both for 5.2 and 5.3.
- Added a overwritten rmdir function that waits until all file change notification handles are closed on a directory
- Added a 1 sec timeout to the overwritten rmdir function in order to avoid process hang
- Fixed an access violation bug caused by concurrent access to the file change notification listener
- Fixed an access violation bug caused by naming collision when creating mutex objects
   </notes>
  </release>
  <release>
   <stability>
    <release>stable</release>
    <api>stable</api>
   </stability>
   <version>
    <release>1.1.0stable</release>
    <api>1.1.0stable</api>
   </version>
   <date>2010-06-30</date>
   <notes>
1.1.0 release:
- Made reroute functionality take out number of parameters it can handle. Also made reroutes only when less or equal number of parameters are passed.
- Added wincache_reroute_list and wrote file apis on top of file cache. Added file flags in fcache_value.
- Removed function hooks which are not giving significant performance boost. Updated version number.
- Added functionality to clear user cache from wincache.php.
- Updated build number for RTW release. Removed rerouteini config property.
   </notes>
  </release>
  <release>
   <stability>
    <release>beta</release>
    <api>beta</api>
   </stability>
   <version>
    <release>1.1.0beta2</release>
    <api>1.1.0beta2</api>
   </version>
   <date>2010-04-29</date>
   <notes>
1.1.0 Beta 2 release:
- updated wincache.php to not show all user cache entries if the total number of entries exceeds 250
- Added summaryonly to all the info functions.
- Separated session cache from user cache. Added wincache_scache_info and wincache_scache_meminfo.
- Made session cache use file backed shared memory so that sessions survive process recycle.
- updated wincache.php to show user cache and session cache informaiton on different pages.
- Calculated memory allocated for storing zval in user cache and exposed it from wincache_ucache_info.
- Distributed file change notification infrastructure to be used with file cache.
- Using pagefile backed shared memory if APP_POOL_ID environment variable is not available.
- Fixed a bug in hashtable copyout. Missed setting hashtable global list tail.
- Added ability to reroute functions in opcode copy code.
- Using file change notification to detect changes to files.
- Create separate session cache for each session.save_path values.
- Added ability to get info on a single user cache entry.
- Exposed functions to get information on folders on which file change notification is active.
- Updated wincache.php to show the content of the user cache entries only if USE_AUTHENTICATION is enabled.
- Added wincache_lock, wincache_unlock APIs. Bug fixes to file change notification and user cache.
- Fixed tickcount rollover related bugs and namesalt truncation bug.
- Bug fixes in usercache. Added optional isglobal to wincache_lock.
- Forcing file change check on folder after listener is moved to different process.
- Fixed fcnotify refcount bug and updated version number for beta2 release.
   </notes>
  </release>
  <release>
   <stability>
    <release>beta</release>
    <api>beta</api>
   </stability>
   <version>
    <release>1.1.0</release>
    <api>1.1.0</api>
   </version>
   <date>2010-03-04</date>
   <notes>
- Added wincache user cache which can be used to store php values in cache.
- Added wincache session handler. Now wincache user cache can be used to store session data.
- Made behavior of user cache functions handle arrays and other key types.
- Fixed a bug in session handler to make it work for SugarCRM.
- Fixed inconsistencies in wincache_ucache APIs. Included session entries lookups in hit/miss counts.
- Updated the wincache.php page to show the informaiton about user and session cache.
   </notes>
  </release>
  <release>
   <stability>
    <release>stable</release>
    <api>stable</api>
   </stability>
   <version>
    <release>1.0.1</release>
    <api>1.0.1</api>
   </version>
   <date>2009-01-26</date>
   <notes>
- Fixed require_once on PHP5.3. If the files were absolute and similar files were included in different case, require_once was including it twice.
- Changed relative path cache to act as resolve path cache. Incremented refcounts under aplist lock. Did comparison using InterlockedCompareExchange.
- Fixed crashes which were happening because aplist refcount and opcode cache refcount can get out of sync due to local cache.
- Exposed is_local_cache property from ocache_fileinfo and fcache_fileinfo. Stats page will use this to indicate when local opcode data is shown.
- Updated the wincache.php to pass chart data on query string to ensure that the charts show the same data that is displayed in tables
- Updated the wincache.php to show whether information about a global or local cache instance is being displayed
- Changed variable names and comments to indicate rplist is resolve path cache and not just relative path cache
- Changed wincache.php to use resolve_path instead of relative_path
   </notes>
  </release>
  <release>
   <stability>
    <release>stable</release>
    <api>stable</api>
   </stability>
   <version>
    <release>1.0.0</release>
    <api>1.0.0</api>
   </version>
   <date>2009-11-19</date>
   <notes>
- Setting absentry and same_value in rplist_value under writelock.
- Final v1 RTW build is version 1117.
- Updated the wincache.php to show a warning if opcode cache size is too small and it has been automatically increased.
- Changed minimum/maximum values of fcachesize, ocachesize. Added olocaltest. Forced ocachesize to be atleast 3 times fcachesize.
- Prevent rplist_value same_value field from pointing to itself, else deleteval does double free on same rplist value.
- Rplist, fcache, ocache entries are deleted by same process. Only marking rplist entries deleted when needed.
- Made strings in rplist_value aligned to dword boundary. Other miscellaneous code improvements.
- Converting opened_path to lowercase makes case-sensitive comparison of __FILE__ with realpath() fail. Fixed.
- Process with local opcode cache never does complete remove_aplist_entry now. Added debuglevel 501 and warning codes. Modified asserts.
- Changed cache size default values. Default size of file cache is 32 MB and opcode cache is 96 MB.
- WINCACHE.PHP will now display files in Output cache and File cache in lexicographical sorted way. The same holds true for relative path cache tab.
- First file executed appears duplicate in included_files list because WinCache adds the file in lowercase which is different from PHP core.
- Taken care of zend bailout properly.
- Removing the local entry when an entry in global aplist gets created.
- Scavenger gets disabled if ttlmax value is 0. Also disabled scavenger in processes which create local opcode cache.
- Fix VC6 compatibility.
- Added total memory row for the file cache and opcode cache overview tables. Also re-ordered the colums in the file cache list to be consistent with opcode cache list.
- Added tooltip for statistics column in wincache.php file.
- Added memory usage pie charts to wincache.php file.
- Minor changes to php_wincache. Made is_free unsigned int. Made used_header similar to free_header by adding two dummy size_t.
- Implemented new INI directive FCENABLEDFILER for file cache which is similar to OCENABLEDFILTER for output cache.
- Fixed the wincache.php authenticaiton logic to not conflict with IIS built-in authentication.
- Added the &quot;filelist&quot; id&apos;s to the file list tables to allow usage of page anchors in navigation.
- Modified the chart in wincache.php to display the numbers rounded to 2 digits after decimal point.
   </notes>
  </release>
 </changelog>
</package>
